<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>piano on cc</title>
    <link>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/tags/piano/</link>
    <description>Recent content in piano on cc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cc.poly2d.xyz/tags/piano/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Jupiter (Awaiting Return)</title>
      <link>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2021-03-11_jupiter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2021-03-11_jupiter/</guid>
      <description>https://youtu.be/ndt_UpllxJQ
If Feljin or Ryu were to play the piano, what would they play, and what story would they tell?
That was my thought process going into this project. This piece is inspired by Awaiting Return by Kevin MacLeod, the background music our DM used at one point for the &amp;ldquo;BRB&amp;rdquo; screen (for IRL short rests) in the Phandelver campaign.
That piece itself is a derivative of the middle section of Jupiter, one of the movements from &amp;ldquo;The Planets&amp;rdquo; orchestral suite by Gustav Holst.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eonian</title>
      <link>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-12-25_eonian/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-12-25_eonian/</guid>
      <description>https://youtu.be/zApesb8vqdk
Based on the Animenz arrangement: Video, Sheets.
I remember the first time I heard Animenz&amp;rsquo;s cover of this in 2015, the second chorus (~2:48) gave me goosebumps! It had been on my mind ever since to learn to play this someday.
The movie itself is pretty good IMO. It got a bit of attention back when it came out for using 3DCG, and also because it was screen-written by the one and only Urobucher.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Champion Cynthia</title>
      <link>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-10-07_cynthia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-10-07_cynthia/</guid>
      <description>https://youtu.be/tFrHxj6Cipc
I basically grew up on Pokemon games. And if there&amp;rsquo;s one thing I can tell you about the video game series, you will know when you&amp;rsquo;re about to against a formidable opponent. The music will let you know.
Hailing from &amp;ldquo;the land of piano&amp;rdquo;, Champion Cynthia is no exception. Leading an arsenal of powerful Pokemon that the player likely haven&amp;rsquo;t encountered up to that point, she descends to her throne as the final opponent at the Sinnoh League, ready to crush the player&amp;rsquo;s dreams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>打上花火 / Uchiage Hanabi</title>
      <link>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-08-31_daoko/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-08-31_daoko/</guid>
      <description>https://youtu.be/6YeJs7StCPM
This was my second full arrangement cover! I haven&amp;rsquo;t turned it into sheets yet. Whether or not I end up doing that, piecing this together was a learning experience.
Before I get to anything else - yes the video is SHAKY AF. It&amp;rsquo;s really too bad. Watch it on a small screen - it&amp;rsquo;s not as noticeable 😂
Ever since I watched the original MV this song was on the bucket list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Euterpe</title>
      <link>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-07-27_euterpe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-07-27_euterpe/</guid>
      <description>https://youtu.be/aqBJfW4wmlg
Based on the Animenz arrangement: Video, Sheets.
Another piece from Animenz&amp;rsquo;s Guilty Crown suite of covers, also from his earlier days. It&amp;rsquo;s in the same starting key as Bios but at a slower pace, 3&amp;frasl;4 signature, and a lot more room for expressiveness.
The middle section is the most interesting to play, requiring fast right hand runs in the upper registers, mixed in with occasional slowdown/speedups as an artifact of &amp;ldquo;squeezing in&amp;rdquo; few more notes into the measure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>虹の列車 / Niji no Ressha</title>
      <link>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-06-29_akb0048/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-06-29_akb0048/</guid>
      <description>https://youtu.be/qpgKnphVYQo
Based on the Animenz arrangement: Video, Sheets.
I love the lyrics of these 0048 songs! This one in particular is high energy and catchy, and I also kinda like its use of the &amp;ldquo;canon progression&amp;rdquo;.
This is one of the more difficult Animenz pieces I&amp;rsquo;ve learned to date, and also one of the most fun to play! As usual, there is a story, and I&amp;rsquo;ve added a custom intro that marks a personal turning point, a new beginning, a departure&amp;hellip; and then dove right in:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hedgehog&#39;s Dilemma</title>
      <link>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-05-31_hedgehog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-05-31_hedgehog/</guid>
      <description>https://youtu.be/Zco5ldaFyhA
This cover is based on the scores by Cosmo Pianist. In general this was a good etude for dynamics and dissonant chords. I didn&amp;rsquo;t hold back when it came to expression - overlaying my emotions along with the somber world view that is &amp;lsquo;Neon Genesis Evangelion&amp;rsquo;.
I tapped into some of the heavy scenes from the work for inspiration; think - drowning, choking. Yeah that&amp;rsquo;s pretty fucked up imagery to draw on, but he just wouldn&amp;rsquo;t shut the fuck up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ßios (YT)</title>
      <link>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-04-23_bios/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-04-23_bios/</guid>
      <description>https://youtu.be/5il_kB_4L2s
Based on the Animenz arrangement: Video, Sheets.
Another shot at this song! This time with the new recording environment (and no pressure from live streaming 😅), and also with a new me having gone through some internal turmoil (see the rant posts before this lol).
Post from previous attempt
Outside of the recording quality, this take is arguably not so much better than my previous run, but there are several changes that I&amp;rsquo;d note as improvements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>変わらないもの</title>
      <link>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-03-13_kawaranai_mono/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-03-13_kawaranai_mono/</guid>
      <description>Notes Video: https://youtu.be/_xTmQi57xmk
Sheets: https://gakufu.poly2d.xyz/kawaranaimono.pdf
Writing this retroactively. The cover was posted on Mar 13. Sheets were completed in May afterwards.
My first piano arrangement, and a special song for a special occasion. This initial intent was to present sheets to accompany the video in March. But I ended up abandoning it - the more I tried to work on it, the more I found the idea &amp;ldquo;limiting&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>くちづけDiamond</title>
      <link>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-02-14_weaver/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-02-14_weaver/</guid>
      <description>Notes Based on the Animenz arrangement
 Video: https://youtu.be/P6C3szts5C4 Sheet: https://sheet.host/sheet/IGm7F5  This was a &amp;lsquo;high reach&amp;rsquo; piece for me in terms of difficulty. But it&amp;rsquo;s a special song and a cover had to be done.
The most difficult segments of the song are the chorus which feature fast left-hand jumps. Many retakes were done due to a lack of accuracy here.
While less obvious, &amp;ldquo;first verse&amp;rdquo; at 0:39 (measures 25-32) was also quite challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>千本桜 (YT)</title>
      <link>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2019-12-29_senbon19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2019-12-29_senbon19/</guid>
      <description>Notes First YouTube upload! The previous Periscopes were captured entirely on phone, but this was the first attempt at using an audio interface in search for better sound quality.
I mixed in elements from a few inspirations. Flowering Night from the Touhou series was used at 1:34 (a nod to Niconico covers) and a variation based on Lindsey Stirling&amp;rsquo;s cover at 1:47.
The &amp;ldquo;guitar riff&amp;rdquo; part of the song was skipped in favor of a more gentle bridge and reprise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twice 4th Anniv Medley (live)</title>
      <link>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2019-10-10_twice4th/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2019-10-10_twice4th/</guid>
      <description>🎹 Twice we FANCY YOU (medley) #Twice4thAnniversary #TWICEMakesMeFeelSpecial #Twice #piano #live https://t.co/EZKzmqV0gK
&amp;mdash; Ryu (@poly2d) October 20, 2019  Excerpts  FANCY (~0:00) What is Love? (~2:00) Like OOH-AHH (~3:28) Dance the Night Away (~4:57) Heart Shaker - outro (~6:45)  Notes I stuck to the A-side tracks for this medley. I just used the songs that came to my mind, but if I were to retroactively state a reason for each:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bios - Guilty Crown (live)</title>
      <link>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2019-10-13_bios/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2019-10-13_bios/</guid>
      <description>🎹 Guilty Crown - βios ギルティクラウン OST #Piano #Music https://t.co/mhtr6ELk5O
&amp;mdash; Ryu (@poly2d) October 14, 2019  Notes Based on the Animenz arrangement
 Video: https://youtu.be/DcjUOdeq6G8 Sheet: https://sheet.host/sheet/1uMLWW Original: https://youtu.be/UMCka_vXtL4  The soundtrack of the Guilty Crown series was what led me to find Animenz on youtube in early 2012.
I found his cover of ßios.
I had some lessons during my childhood, but by this time I had absolutely forgotten how to play piano.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>千本桜 / Senbonzakura (live)</title>
      <link>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2019-08-31_senbon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2019-08-31_senbon/</guid>
      <description>🎹 千本桜 / Senbonzakura live piano #初音ミク生誕祭2019 #HatsuneMikuBirthday https://t.co/HNJVg866Mn
&amp;mdash; Ryu (@poly2d) September 1, 2019  Notes  Original: https://youtu.be/P6C3szts5C4  This live of Senbonzakura was for a special occasion: 13th anniversary of Hatsune Miku! I have fond memories of this song because my roommates and I played it a lot in Taiko no Tatsujin.
I borrowed some small nuances and snippets from two of my favorite covers of this song (listed below) - can you spot them?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NGE Medley (live)</title>
      <link>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2019-06-22_nge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2019-06-22_nge/</guid>
      <description>This was the first piano post I shared on Twitter! The hype in this day and age was how Neon Genesis Evangelion was coming to Netflix (at least for a subset of the internet 🙂). That led me to revisit some of the theme songs from the franchise.
🎹ネトフリにエヴァ来たらしいのでOPとか弾いてみる/ Songs from the anime Neon Genesis Evangelion (live piano) #evangelion https://t.co/0D1wohnbiB
&amp;mdash; Ryu (@poly2d) June 22, 2019  Excerpts  残酷な天使のテーゼ / Cruel Angel’s Thesis (TV Series OP) (Transition) [SPOILER WARNING] Ep 19 初号機が暴走する時のBGM / Unit-1 goes berserk Fly me to the moon (TV Series ED) Beautiful world (Rebuild 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>