<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>youtube on cc</title>
    <link>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/tags/youtube/</link>
    <description>Recent content in youtube on cc</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cc.poly2d.xyz/tags/youtube/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ßios (YT)</title>
      <link>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-04-23_bios/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-04-23_bios/</guid>
      <description>Notes https://youtu.be/5il_kB_4L2s
Based on the Animenz arrangement: Video, Sheets.
Another shot at this song! This time with the new recording environment (and no pressure from live streaming 😅), and also with a new me having gone through some internal turmoil (see the rant posts before this lol).
Post from previous attempt
Outside of the recording quality, this take is arguably not so much better than my previous run, but there are several changes that I&amp;rsquo;d note as improvements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>変わらないもの</title>
      <link>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-03-13_kawaranai_mono/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-03-13_kawaranai_mono/</guid>
      <description>Notes Video: https://youtu.be/_xTmQi57xmk
Sheets: https://gakufu.poly2d.xyz/kawaranaimono.pdf
Writing this retroactively. The cover was posted on Mar 13. Sheets were completed in May afterwards.
My first piano arrangement, and a special song for a special occasion. This initial intent was to present sheets to accompany the video in March. But I ended up abandoning it - the more I tried to work on it, the more I found the idea &amp;ldquo;limiting&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>くちづけDiamond</title>
      <link>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-02-14_weaver/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2020-02-14_weaver/</guid>
      <description>Notes Based on the Animenz arrangement
 Video: https://youtu.be/P6C3szts5C4 Sheet: https://sheet.host/sheet/IGm7F5  This was a &amp;lsquo;high reach&amp;rsquo; piece for me in terms of difficulty. But it&amp;rsquo;s a special song and a cover had to be done.
The most difficult segments of the song are the chorus which feature fast left-hand jumps. Many retakes were done due to a lack of accuracy here.
While less obvious, &amp;ldquo;first verse&amp;rdquo; at 0:39 (measures 25-32) was also quite challenging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>千本桜 (YT)</title>
      <link>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2019-12-29_senbon19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cc.poly2d.xyz/posts/2019-12-29_senbon19/</guid>
      <description>Notes First YouTube upload! The previous Periscopes were captured entirely on phone, but this was the first attempt at using an audio interface in search for better sound quality.
I mixed in elements from a few inspirations. Flowering Night from the Touhou series was used at 1:34 (a nod to Niconico covers) and a variation based on Lindsey Stirling&amp;rsquo;s cover at 1:47.
The &amp;ldquo;guitar riff&amp;rdquo; part of the song was skipped in favor of a more gentle bridge and reprise.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>